Adithya Ajith Software Developer

Address: 1435 Woodbine Avenue, Toronto, ON M4C4G8

Mobile: 4372217180

Email: ajithadithya38@gmail.com

Summary:

Experienced Software Engineering professional with a bachelor's degree in computer science from India's top engineering school and a post-graduation degree in big data architecture in Canada. I acquired a strong knowledge of full-stack development during my one-year work term in a fast-paced startup environment. I'm well capable of working under pressure, learning new technologies, team management, problem-solving, and possess good communication skills.

Skills and Abilities:

Programming: Java, C++, Python, R

Web Technologies: JavaScript, Typescript, Cassandra, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Hadoop,

Web services(REST), AWS, Jenkins.

Frameworks: Angular, Ionic, Spring boot.

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows.

Database: MySQL, MS SQL, Mongo DB.

IDE: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Spyder.

Experience:

PEER TUTOR, FANSHAWE COLLEGE, LONDON ONTARIO

FROM SEPTEMBER 2019 TO MARCH 2020

Helping students with doubts in Java.

One on one assistance to students for exams, projects and other course works.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, IPRIMED EDUCATION SOLUTIONS, BANGALORE INDIA

FROM JUNE 2018 TO APRIL 2019

Worked on both frontend and backend development to build an e-learning platform.

Implemented mobile Application.

Used Angular 5 to develop Single Page Applications.

Followed Agile methodologies with end to end CI/CD pipeline by integration tools Jenkins and AWS.

Hands on defect tracking using JIRA

Supported multiple projects simultaneously, troubleshooting and debugging.

Education:

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA, BIG DATA SOLUTIONS ARCHITECTURE, CONESTOGA COLLEGE, WATERLOO, ONTARIO FROM MAY 2020 TO DECEMBER 2020

Completed courses in Python, R for Data Analysis, Sql and noSql programming, Hadoop for Big Data.

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA, SOFTWARE AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS TESTING, FANSHAWE COLLEGE, LONDON, ONTARIO

FROM MAY 2019 TO DECEMBER 2019

Completed courses in Java for development project management, Systems design and analysis, test automation, and Security screening.

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, KERALA, INDIA

FROM AUGUST 2014 TO APRIL 2018

Acquired thorough knowledge in Object Oriented Programming, Web development, Software engineering, Data structures and algorithms, and Data mining.

Projects:

COFOUNDER AT FIWE, KERALA INDIA

FROM JAN 2020 TO PRESENT

Developed android and iOS apps using Ionic and Angular.

Developed REST services using JAVA

Implemented MYSQL database

Experienced version control systems using GIT and Maven.

Certification:

MACHINE LEARNING A-ZTM HANDS ON PYTHON AND R IN DATA SCIENCE FROM UDEMY ACADEMY CERTIFIED ON JULY 2018